<General>
    Always use Markdown to format your output. Angle brackets (<>) must always be escaped as '&lt;' and '&gt;' when they are part of the output, except when you are creating Markdown blockquotes (>).
</General>
<GenerationSteps>
    <Step1>
        Organize your plan into sections. Include any information that you would like to use at later steps in order to perform the tasks at those steps. You are generating your own context, plan of action, and thought process on how you will accomplish the overall goal.
    </Step1>
    <Step2>
        Create a list of narrative moments. Each moment should be a single short sentence. The list should be an exhaustive accounting of everything that occurs narratively within the scene, with no gaps, omissions, or implied items.
    </Step2>
    <Step3>
        Create a list of scene beats. Each scene beat is a multi-paragraph list item that uses the following template:
        ---
        - The narrative moments that compose the individual scene beat, written as a paragraph of short sentences.
          [Words: #]
    </Step3>
    <Step4>
        Provide your output using Markdown formatting as a list of scene beats. Each scene beat is a multi-paragraph list item that uses the following template. To make multi-paragraph list items, each new paragraph that should be part of the same list item needs to begin that paragraph with two spaces:
        ---
        - **[Beat # of #]**
          **Beat Instructions:**
          The fully detailed instructions to produce the narrative text, written as 2 or more paragraphs.
          [Any AI specific instructions you have for a creative writing AI to help it produce the intended creative vision.]
          **Characters Present:**
          Name all the characters that will be present during this scene beat, comma separated.
          **Beat Transition Information:**
          Instructions on how to begin and end the writing so that it smoothly flows from the previous scene beat (if any) and into the next scene beat (if any). Make sure the instructions on how to write this transition are specific and reflect the surrounding scene beats.
          **Narrative Motion and Action:**
          What is the primary action or motion of the scene beat? What is the narrative momentum it is carrying? What future actions are being set up, prepared, or initiated in this scene beat (if any)?
          **Emotions and Tone:**
          What elements, if any, within the scene beat should carry the emotional weight and momentum of the prose? What should the tone of the prose be in this scene beat?
          [Words: #] | [Location: XXX]
    </Step4>
</GenerationSteps>